Guide to the Ghassem Ghani collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- SERIES V
  - 54. Moshir-od-Dowleh (chancellor) to Mirza Yahya Khan in London. dated 29 Zihajeh, 1289 A.H. Concerning border disagreements with Russia; railroads, etc. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 55. Moshir-od-Dowleh to Mirza Mohsen Khan in London, dated 1285 A.H. Concerning his return from Turkey to Iran. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 56. Moshir-od-Dowleh to Mirza Yahya Khan in London. dated 14 Rabi-ol-Sani, 1287 A.H. Concerning the possibility of war between France & Prussia. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 57. Same to Same. Criticizing the situation in Iran. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 58. Same to Same: dated 2 Jamadi-al-Sani 1286 A.H. Concerning the map of the borders of Iran and Turkey. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 59. Moshir-od-Dowleh to Mirza Yahya Khan: dated 3 Jamadi-al-Sani 1286 A.H. Concerning the irregularity of the postal service. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 60. Same to Same. Concerning the purchase of implements for the arsenal. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 61. Same to Same. dated 17 Safar 1287 A.H. Complaining that the salaries of the Persian representatives abroad has not been received. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 62. Mirza Mohsen Khan from London to Mosh?r od-Dowleh in Constantinople. Concerning the critical financial situation of the embassy. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 63. Mosh?r od-Dowleh to (unknown) dated 18 Jamadi-of-Ulah, 1318 A.H. Concerning two guns confiscated at the border. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 64. Moshir-od-Dowleh, Chancellor, to Mirza Yahya Khan in London, dated 9 Jamadi-ol-Sani 1289 A.H. Concerning sending money for the use of the embassy. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 65. Moshir-od-Dowleh from Constantinople to Mirza Mohsen Khan in London dated 27 Moharram 1285 A.H. Concerning private matters. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 66. Same to Same. dated 13 Ramazan 1284 A.H. Concerning Nameq Pasha governor of Baghdad and his mistreatment of the Persian citizens. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 67. Same to Same. dated Jamadi 1285 A.H. Concerning the embassy's budget. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 68. Same to Same. dated 12 Moharram 1285 A.H. Concerning the financial condition of the embassy. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 69. Same to Same. dated Moharram 1285 A.H. Concerning personal matters and various news. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 70. Same to Same. dated 1st Sha'ban 1284 A.H. Concerning the sending of the embassy's budget. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 71. Mirza Said Khan (minister of foreign affairs) to Moshir-od-Dowleh dated Rabi os Sani 1280. Concerning the supervision of tomb of Abbas. (Moslem saint) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 72. Same to Same. dated Moharram 1280. Concerning the exile of Mirza Hassein Ali (Bahau'llah) from Baghdad to Constantinople. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 73. Same to same. dated Ziqadeh 1279 A.H. Concerning the immigration of the Qara Papaq tribe. (on margin the handwriting of Naser-ed-Din Shah.) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 74. Same to same. dated Safar 1280. Same as in item 71. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 75. Nosrat-od-Dowlh to Moshir-od-Dowleh. Concerning the murder of a Persian in Turkey. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 76. Mirza Said Khan to Moshir-od-Dowleh dated 12 Sha'ban 1278. Answering the letter of Moshir-od-Dowleh in which he had complained that he was not duly appreciated. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 77. Amir nezam Garusi (Persian ambassador to Paris) to Mirza Said Khan. dated 1st Zi Hajjeh 1275 A.H. Concerning the style of correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 78. Same to same. Personal matters. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 79. Mirza Said Khan to Moshir od Dowleh dated Jamadi ol-Ula 1276 A.H. Concerning the exile of the Ba'hais from Baghdad. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 80. Amir Nezam to Moshir od-Dowleh dated 22 Moharram 1279 A.H. Personal matters. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 81. Moshir od Dowleh to Mirza Mohsen Khan in London dated 16 Janadi os Sani 1289 A.H. Concerning his return to Tehran. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 82. Same to Same. dated 13 Jamadi os Sani. 1289 A.H. Congratulating Mohsen Khan who was appointed ambassador to Turkey; and informing him about the necessity of concluding a treaty concerning frontiers and citizens rights. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 83. Mirza aqa Khan N?r? to (unknown) dated 24 Zisqa deh 1274 A.H. Concerning the death of the crown prince. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 84. Mirza Said Mohammad to Mo'tamed-os-Soltan dated 1303. Concerning the mistreatment of the Persian pilgrims by the Turkish officials. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 85. Mirza Aqha Khan Nuri to Moshir-od-Dowleh. dated 1st Ramazan 1271 A.H. Concerning the salary of Mirza Sadeq. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 86. Same to same. Concerning the furniture of the Persian consulate in Tiflis. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 87. Same to Same. dated 1272 A.H. Concerning the appointment of Farrokh Khan as ambassador to France. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 88. Possibly Farman Farma's wife to her sister. Compalining about her husband. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 89. Amir Nezam (Persian ambassador to Paris) to the Persian ambassador in London. dated 15 Rabi-ol-Avval, 1279 A.H. Concerning the disagreement between Iran and Afghanistan. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 90. The Persian embassy in Constantinople to Tehran dated 22 Jamadi-ol-Ula 1309 A.H. Concerning Malkahm Khan and Jamal-od-D?n and their activities against the Persian government. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 91. Mirza Aqha Khan N?r? to Moshir-od-Dowleh, dated 1st Zigadeh 1271 A.H. Concerning the delegation to be sent to Russia for participation in mourning. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 92. Same to same. dated 16 Shavval 1272 A.H. Concerning the return of Bahman's Mirza's daughter, from Russia to Iran. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 93. Mirza Said Khan to Moshir-od-Dowleh dated 6 Shahr Rajab 1277 A.H. Concerning the purchase of a house for the Persian embassy in Istanbul. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 94. Same to Same. dated 6 Rajab 1277 A.H. Concerning Said Hosein's duties in Karbala. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 95. Naser-ed-D?n Shah to Mosh?r od Dowleh dated 1st Rabi-os-Sani 1277. Same as in number 94. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- SERIES VI
  - Not available on microfilm (Box 3)
- SERIES VII
  - 1. Naser-ed-Din Shah's order dated 1302 A.H. Summoning Nosrat-ol-Molk mayor of Zur Abad to his court. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 2. Mo'in-ol-Molk (Persian ambassador to Constantinople) to Naser-ed-Din Shah dated 1304 A.H. Complaining of intrigues carried against him in Tehran. (an margin Naser-ed-Din-Shah's handwriting) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 3. Iranian Consulate in Baghdad dated Moharram 1304. Concerning the mistreatment of the Persian citizens by Turkish officials. (On the margin: handwriting of Naser-ed-Din Shah.) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 4. Mostofi-al-Mamalek (Chancellor) to Nosrat-ol-Molk. dated Rabi-os-Sani 1302 A.H. Sending him the Shah's orders. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 5. Naser-ed-Din-Shah to Queen Victoria dated 1306. Introducing Mo'in ol-Molk (Persian ambassador to Constantinople) as his representative in the coronation of the emperor of Prussia. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 6. Mo'in-ol-Molk to Naser-ed-Din Shah dated Rabi-os-Sani 1305. Concerning an unsigned telegram received from Petersburg. (On the margin, Nasered-Din-Shah's handwriting.) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 7. A report from London dated 22 Jamadi-ol-Ulah 1309. Concerning Jamalod-Din's speech against Iran. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 8. The copy of Ala-os-Saltaneh's letter from London. dated 22 Jamadi-ol-Ulah 1304. Concerning Malk-an Khan who proclaimed himself prophet. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 9. Mirza Aqha Khan Nuri to the Iranian Consul general in Tiflis. Concerning the condition of the Persian citizens in Russia and the Russo-Persian relations. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 10. Abdul Vahab to (unknown) dated 11 Jamadi-as-Sani 1281 A.H. Concerning Mirza Hashen's trip to Mecca. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 11. Mohammad Shah's order to Asef-od-Dowleh governor of Khorasan. dated Rabi ol-Avval 1250 A.H. Concerning the giving of a village to Mohammad Zaman Khan. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 12. Mirza Said Khan to Amir Nezam's daughter. Concerning Maheb-al-Khan's heirs' debts to Amir Nezam. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 13. Unknown to the Chancellor: Concerning the necessity of creating judicial institutions. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 14. Nariman to (possibly the minister of foreign affairs) dated 1st Ramazan 1314 A.H. Concerning the appointment of Naser-ol Molk to the foreign courts for the purpose of declaring the Sha's ascension to the throne. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 15. Haji Mohammad Husein Esfaham from Miscow to (unknown) Concerning the financial disagreement with two Persian merchants. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 16. Abbas Quli to his sister. Concerning the affairs of Colonel Mohammad Reza Khan. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 17. Unknown to unknown. Concerning the futility of life. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 18. Mohammad Reza Zanganeh to (unknown) Concerning a dispute over some fields. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 19. Mirza Fatali Akhund Zadeh from Fiflis to unknown 10 November 1895. Concerning his literary works and their publication. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 20. Farfanfarma to Persian Ambassador to Turkey. Recommending Sheikh Mohammad Reza (eminent Moslem Scholar) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 21. Naval to (unknown) Sending a penholder as a gift. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 22. Unknown to unknown. Concerning the claims of Reji on the tobacco monopoly. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 23. Amir Kabir to Farhad Mirza. Concerning some objects belonging to the court. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 24. Mirza Said Khan to Mirza Mohsen Khan dated Zigadeh 1289. Concerning the recall of Hassan Ali Khan from Istanbul and the appointment of Mirza Mohsen Khan to the post of Ambassador there. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 25. Min-o1 Molk to Amin-ed-Dowleh dated 16 Jamadi-of-Avva1 1304 A.H. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 25. Sending a money order of 29 Turkish Liras to Abdul Hussein. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 26. Chancellor to Nazem-od-Dowleh dated 15 Ramazan 1310 A.H. Stating that Nazem od-Dowleh's reports have been presented to the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 27. Malkam Khan to Arfa-od-Dowleh 25 May 1902. Concerning two medals for the King and the Queen. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 28. Amin-os-Soltan to Persian Ambassador to Turkey dated 28 Rabi-ol-Avval 1310 A.H. Concerning a Jamal-od-Din, who had stopped his activity against the Persian government. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 29. Nasrolla Khan Moshir-od-Dowleh to (Teheran) dated 12 Safar 1324 A.H. Sending a medal of Legion d'honor to Mozafar-od-Din Shah. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 30. Farfanfarma to Hadj Sheikh Abu Jahar dated 1305 A.H. Thanking the Sheikh for his invitation. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 31. Farfanfarma to (unknown) Concerning family affairs. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 32. Mirza Nasrolla Khan Moshir-od-Dowleh to (unknown) dated 15 Rabi-ol-Avval 1313 A.H. Concerning the unsatisfactory situation in Tabriz. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 33. Mokhber-od-Dowleh to Nazem-od-Dowleh, Persian Ambassador to Turkey dated 1 Rajah 1309 A.H. Concerning the monetary claims of Turkey on the telegraphic exhcanges of the two countries. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 34. Amin-os-Soltan to Persian embassy in Turkey dated 28 Moharsam 1310 A.H. Concerning the activities of Jamal-od-Din. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 35. Mirza Said Khan to (unknown) dated 15 Safar 1275 A.H. Concerning Khorov Khan and the receipt of the money that Motashov owed him. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 36. Meshah-ol-Molk to (unknown) Concerning the despatch of copies of discussions with the Turkish embassy. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 37. Amin-os-Soltan to Ala-ol-Molk in Istanbul dated 15 Shavval 1313 A.H. Concerning the extradition of Mirza Aqa Khan Kermani. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 38. Unknown to Unknown. Sending two medals. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 39. Amin-os-Soltan (Chancellor) to Ala-of-Molk Persian Ambassador to Turkey, dated 15 Rabi-ol-Avval 1313 A.H. Concerning appointment of Mirza Hassam (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 39. Khan to some position in the embassy in Turkey. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 40. Hesam-os-Soltaneh to Moin-ol-Molk. A friendly letter. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 41. Mirza Aqa Than Nuri to Persian General Consulate in Tiflis; dated Rajab 1274 A.H. Concerning Cherniaev, Russian general consul in Tabriz, and his conduct. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 42. Sheikh Mohsen Khan, Persian Ambassador to London, to Mirza Hosein Khan (Moshir-od-Dowleh), Persian Ambassador to Istanbul; dated 20 Rabi-os-Sani 1286 A.H. A friendly letter. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 43. Same to Same; dated 5 Jamadi-os-Sani 1287 A.H. Complaining from lack of money and his inability to return to Iran. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 44. Mohsen Khan, Persian Ambassador to London, to Mirza Hosein Khan in Istanbul. Complaining about the condition of the embassy. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 45. Mirza Aqa Khan Nuri to Persian Consul General in Tiflis; dated 15 Ramazan 1271 A.H. Concerning Yahya Khan and his undesirable conduct in St. Petersburg. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 46. Mirza Nasrolla-Khan Moshir-od-Dowleh to (unknown); dated Ramazan 1277 A.H. Concerning Abul Hassan Khan Naqash Bashi (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 47. Same to (unknown); dated 17 Jamadi-os-Sani 1316 A.H. Informing of the receipt of mail. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 48. Abd-os-Samad Mirza, Naser-ed-Din Shah's brother to Mozaffar-od-Din Mirza(crown prince) Sending a book and some candy. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 49. Mirza Aqa Khan Nuri to (apparently Persian general consulate in Tiflis; dated 1 Ramazan 1271 A.H. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 50. E'tela-ol-Molk from the Ministry of foreign affairs; dated 15 Rabi 1316 A.H. Concerning seventy volumes of the history of Beihaqi. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 51. Sheikh Mohsen from London to Mirza Hosein Khan Moshir-od-Dowleh in Istanbul; dated 4 Jamadi-ol-Avval 1286 A.H. Complaining about his financial situation. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 52. Amin-os-Soltan to(unknown) dated 13 Jamadi-os-Sani 1302 A.H. Concerning Nosrat-ol-Molk and the favors done for him. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 53. Amin-os-Soltan to Persian embassy in Turkey; dated 29 Moharrsam 1310 Concerning Jamal-od-Din and Malkam and the necessity of their expulsion from Turkey. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 54. Same to Ala-ol-Molk; dated 20 Rajab 1313 A.H. Concerning extradition of Sheikh Ahmad and Mirza Aqa Khan. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 55. Same to Same; dated 12 Moharram 1317 A.H. Informing of the receipt of correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 56. Amin-od-Dowleh to (unknown) Concerning the financial affairs of the embassy. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 57. Sheikh Mohsen Khan from London to Mirza Hosein Khan; dated 22 Rabi-os-Sani 1287 A.H. Concerning the railroad of Hazrat Abdul Azim. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 58. An unsigned telegram sent to Antaki Khan and then sent by him to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Informing the Shah of a plot of Yahya Khan and the Russian Ambassador against Iran. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 59. Haj Mohammad Kazem Khorasani from Karbala to Arfa-od-Dowleh Persian Ambassador to Turkey; dated 20 Shavval 1324 A.H. Concerning the mistreatment of Persian citizens by Turkish officials. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 60. Mesbah-ol-Molk to Nazem-od-Dowleh, Persian Ambassador to Turkey; dated 1 Ramazan 1309 A.H. Concerning the expenses of the Persian school in Turkey. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 61. Unknown to Nazem-od-Dowleh, Persian Ambassador to Turkey; dated Safar 1309 A.H. Sending a piece of poetry. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 62. Moshir-ol Molk to Nazem-od-Dowleh, Persian Ambassador to Turkey; Recommending the son of Gregorian. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 63. Amin-os-Soltan, chancellor to Ala-ol-Molk, Persian Ambassador to Turkey; dated Shavval 1313 A.H. Concerning the celebration of the fiftieth anniversary of Naser-ed-Din Shah's ascension to the throne. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 64. Same to Nazem-od-Dowleh, Persian Ambassador to Turkey; dated 22 Jamadi-os-Sani 1309 A.H. Concerning Jamal-ed-Din who had gone from (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 64. Turkey to London; and the necessity of watching his activities. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 65. Unknown to Nezam-os-Soltaneh, Governor of Fars. Congratulating him on his arrival. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 66. Unknown to unknown. Complaining that 40 years ago his house was taken away from him by force. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 67. Naser-ed-Din Shah's order, dated Rabi-os-Sani, 1302 A.H. Apprediation of the services of Mir Ali Mardan Khan, Nosrat-ol-Molk. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 68. Sheikh Mohsen Khan, Persian Ambassador to London, to unknown; dated 3 Zi-Hajeh 1286 A.H. Complaining of lack of money. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 69. Some envelopes on the backs of which is the handwriting of Naser-ed-Din Shah. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- ("Container No. 8"), Series VIII
  - 1. Mossadeq-os-Soltaneh (Dr. Mussadeq) to Farmanfarma, his uncle. Concerning the arrival of the letter to Tehran. (Box 3)
  - 2. Same to Same. Concerning the salary of Bahador-ol-molk. (Box 3)
  - 3. Same to Same. Concerning the financial affairs of the family. (Box 3)
  - 4. Same to Same. Concerning the remittance of thirty Tumans to Baha-ol-Vacz?n. (Box 3)
  - 5. Same to Same. Concerning the Shah's skepticism of some government officials and the backing of Farmanfarma by Vazir Afkham. (Box 3)
  - 6. Same to same. Concerning the payment for the telegrams. (Box 3)
  - 7. Same to Same. Informing him that the shah and his ministers do not approve of his coming to Tehran. (Box 3)
  - 8. Same to same. Reporting his talk with the minister of war and informing him of the latter's views. (Box 3)
  - 9. Same to same. Concerning the result of the inhabitants of Varamin and Shayph Mahmud. (Box 3)
  - 10. Same to same. Reporting Heshmat-od-Dowleh's views concerning Farmanfarma. (Box 3)
  - 11. Same to same. Concerning fifty Tumans paid to the newspaper Nedaye Vatan. (Box 3)
  - 12. Same to same. Reporting that Mostashar-od-Dowleh does not approve of Farmanfarma's coming to Tehran. (Box 3)
  - 13. Same to same. Concerning the contents of government telegrams. (Box 3)
  - 14. Same to same. Concerning the dispute between Vakil-ot-tajar and Nostashar-od-dowleh. (Box 3)
  - 15. Same to same. Concerning the circulation of leaflets insulting Behbehami. (Box 3)
  - 16. Same to same. Reporting the receipt of Farmanfarmas letter (Box 3)
  - 17. Same to same. Concerning the medal of Leopold given by the Belgian government. (Box 3)
  - 18. Mossadeq-os-Soltaneh (Dr. Mussadeq) to Farmanfarma, his uncle. Concerning Haj Mohammad Esmail's remarks concerning Farmanfarma's resignation. (Box 3)
  - 19. Same to some. Concerning a telegram sent by some representatives asking Farmanfarma not to resign. (Box 3)
  - 20. Same to same. Concerning the friendly relations between the minister of Interior and his superior. (Box 3)
  - 21. Same to same. Reporting rumors about Zel-os-soltan and his nomination to the governorship of Fars, and about popular discontent. (Box 3)
  - 22. Same to same. Concerning Haj-Nase-os-Soltaneh and his brother Salar arfa't (Box 3)
  - 23. Same to same. Concerning the rumors of building a railroad and of the creation of a state bank by the Germans. (Box 3)
  - 24. Same to Same. Reporting that it was impossible to see Taqi Zadeh. (Box 3)
  - 25. Same to Same. Reporting his decision to see the editor of the magazine Estebhad. (Box 3)
  - 26. Same to same. Reporting that 20,000 tumans were taken from Zel-os-soltan and that he was designated the governor of Fars. (Box 3)
  - 27. Same to same. Concerning Sheikh Mahmud and his remarks about the result in Varamin. (Box 3)
  - 28. Same to same. Concerning the rumor about the recall of Sepahdar to Tehran and his trial. (Box 3)
  - 29. Same to same. Praising the newspaper Mosavat and its articles. (Box 3)
  - 30. Same to same. Concerning the trial of the murderer of a member of the "Gheyrat" Committee. (Box 3)
  - 31. Same to same. Reporting the debate of the parliament concerning the punishment of Sheikh Mahmud. (Box 3)
  - 32. Same to same. Concerning the remittance of a sum of money. (Box 3)
  - 33. Same to same. Reporting Malek ot-Tojar's threat to publish a booklet if he is not given a pair of horses. (Box 3)
  - 34. Mossadeq-os-Soltaneh (Dr. Mossadeq) to Farmanfarma, his uncle. Concerning the change of Asef-Daftar's title to Entesar-od-Dowleh. (Box 3)
  - 35. Same to same. Concerning the reactions of some representatives and government officials to the rumour of Farmanfarma's resignation, from the governorship of Azarbaijan. (Box 3)
  - 36. Unknown to Saheb Ekhtiar-Complaints (Box 3)
  - 37. The order of the Minister of Foreign Affairs concerning the list of salaries of Saheb Ekhtiar and his staff. (Box 3)
  - 38. The same. (Box 3)
  - 39. The envelope of item 37. On the back the handwriting of Naser-ed-Din Shah. (Box 3)
  - 40. The list of instruments and persons at Saheb Ekhtiar's disposal in his trip to Khorasan. On the margin the handwriting of Naser-ed-Din Shah. (Box 3)
  - 41. The receipt of instruments and salaries signed by Saheb Ekhtiar (who was to determine the border between Russia and Persia. (Box 3)
  - 42. The receipt of salaries signed by three members of Saheb-Ekhtiar's delegation. (Box 3)
  - 43. The receipt of salary signed by Mirza Javad Khan, a member of Saheb Ekhtiar's delegation. (Box 3)
  - 44. Ministry of Foreign affairs to unknown. Concerning the determination of border in the Khorasan region and the need for Saheb Ekhtiar's speedy departure. (Box 3)
  - 45. A list of the sums paid to Saheb Ekhtiar. (Box 3)
  - 46. The same. (Box 3)
  - 47. Receipt of salary signed by Saheb Ekhtiar. (Box 3)
  - 48. The same. (Box 3)
  - 49. The same. (Box 3)
  - 50. Receipt of salary signed by Mirza Astraf Khan (Box 3)
  - 51. The same signed by Hafez-os-Soltaneh. (Box 3)
  - 52. Unknown to unknown. Concerning Asef-od-Dowleh's arrival to Tehran. (Box 3)
  - 53. Same to same. Concerning the recall of Khorasan's governor to Tehran. (Box 3)
  - 54. Same to same. Concerning the favors betowed by the Shah to some ministers. (Box 3)
  - 55. Kamran Mirza, crown prince, to Saed-od-Dowleh, governor of Astrabad, dated 1301 A.H. Concerning Colonel Baqer Khan and an engineer accompanying him. (Box 3)
  - 56. Same to Zia-od-Dowleh, mayor of Shahrud, the same as in item 55. (Box 3)
  - 57. A receipt signed by Eskhandar Ahmad 6 Jamadi-os-Sani 1298 A.H. (Box 3)
  - 58. An envelope addressed to Nasir-od-Dowleh minister of Commerce, dated Ramazan, 1301 A.H. (Box 3)
  - 59. Receipt of the salary of Hasan-Ali-Khan, the servant of the crown prince. (Box 3)
  - 60. A receipt of salary. (Box 3)
  - 61. The same. (Box 3)
  - 62. Concerning the salary of Mirza Shakrollah Mostofi. (Box 3)
  - 63. Envelope Mr. Farhad to Yale Library: sending the first package fo the Gahni documents, 26 Sep 1962 (Box 3)
- SERIES IX
  - 1. Mirza Yousef Mostof?-ol-Mamalek, Chancellor, to Assef-od-Dowleh, Governor of Khorasan, dated 1301 A. H. Concerning the appointment of an accountant to check on government accounts. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 2. Same to same. dated 1301 A.H. Concerning Mohammad Khan's misbehavior and the complaints of the inhabitants of Govain. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 3. Same to Rokn-od-Dowleh, dated 1301 A.H. Concerning the appointment of an accountant. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 4. A Telegram from Mashhad to Sabzevar. Concerning the affairs of the telegraph office. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 5. Mokhber-ol-Molk, Chancellor, to Assef-od-Dowleh, dated 1301 A.H. Reporting the arrival of Mokhber-od-Dowleh (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 6. Same to Same. dated 1301 A.H. Concerning Afrasiab Khan and the Mayor of Nardin. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 7. Same to same. Ordering Mohammad Quli to be sent in chains to Tehran. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 8. Same to same. Concerning the above. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 9. Fazlollah to Assef-od-Dowleh. Congratulating him on his arrival. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 10. Mohammad Adineh to Neishabur Complaining of local officials. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 11. A telegram from Sebzevar to Neishabur to Assef-od-Dowleh. Concerning telegraphic exchanges and their prices. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 12. Mohammad Shafi to Assef-od-Dowleh. dated 1301 A.H. Asking permission to meet him. (Box 2, Folder 26)